<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Picovico Blog</title><link href="http://blog.picovico.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://blog.picovico.com/feeds/.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://blog.picovico.com/</id><updated>2015-05-21T06:34:10+05:45</updated><entry><title>Make Youtube videos more interactive with the new 'Cards'</title><link href="http://blog.picovico.com/make-youtube-video-more-interactive-with-cards.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-05-21T06:34:10+05:45</updated><author><name>PICOVICO</name></author><id>tag:blog.picovico.com,2015-04-21:make-youtube-video-more-interactive-with-cards.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Recently Youtube introduced a new feature called "Cards" for video publishers. If you have been publishing on this platform, you’ve probably used annotations to engage with your viewers. There were some limitation with it especially the kind of info you could share using it. And most importantly it is incompatibilty over mobile devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new Cards are an improved form of those annotations and will eventually replace them. As Youtube puts it, "They can inform your viewers about other videos, merch, playlists, websites and more. They look as beautiful as your videos, are available anytime during the video and yes, they finally work on mobile."
There are six types of cards to choose from: Merchandise, Fundraising, Video, Playlist, Associated Website and Fan Funding. The list will increase with time and you’ll find a new “Cards” tab in your Video Editor to create and edit them at any time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Lanscape mode- Cards let you make videos interactive on YouTube." src="http://blog.picovico.com/theme/images/youtube-cards/landscape.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;small&gt;Youtube card when clicked in landscape mode on mobile device.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Portrait mode- Cards let you make videos interactive on YouTube." src="http://blog.picovico.com/theme/images/youtube-cards/portrait.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;small&gt;Youtube card when clicked in portrait mode on mobile device.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The interdevice compatibility of cards gives publisher more flexibility to share what they want.  We're liking the feature from our initial trial uses. You should try it out too. If you have any innovative idea in which this feature can be used, share with us in the comments below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make slideshow videos of your digital content to engage and entertain audience. &lt;a href="http://picovico.com"&gt;Learn More.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Picovico collaborates with Rotaract for video contest</title><link href="http://blog.picovico.com/picovico-collaborates-with-rotaract-for-video-contest.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-04-05T11:15:20+05:45</updated><author><name>PICOVICO</name></author><id>tag:blog.picovico.com,2015-04-05:picovico-collaborates-with-rotaract-for-video-contest.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Rotaract Nepal and Picovico have together launched a video making contest for the members of Rotaract. Rotaract&amp;apos;s recent meeting held in Kathmandu saw members and presidents from different district chapters throughout Nepal being a part of a day-long session. This session discussed on taking clubs forward, training to improve club activities and planning the upcoming year at the clubs. And as a part of the drive to engage people more with the club, the video contest was launched.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this contest, participants will be required to make slideshow video using Picovico Slideshow Maker app on their Android device and submit it. The theme for video making is #MyYearsinRotartact. The best video stories will be short listed among which the final winners will be selected. The winning videos will get the privilege of being shown to all Rotaract members and also take away attractive prize. Details of the contest will soon be posted on this blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The aim of this contest is to bring out some interesting stories that people have to share with others. It will act as a platform to communicate their message to a big mass of people and since Picovico videos are easy to make, anyone with basic knowledge of using a smartphone can participate. So if this sounds interesting to you, stay connected with this on our social channels as we release all the details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more info, write to us at info@picovico.com with the subject "Video contest".&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="Content"></category><category term="collaboration"></category><category term="Picovico"></category><category term="Rotaract"></category></entry><entry><title>When we reached 50K installs of Picovico Slideshow Maker on Android</title><link href="http://blog.picovico.com/when-we-reached-50k-installs-of-picovico-slideshow-maker-on-android.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-04-03T06:34:10+05:45</updated><author><name>PICOVICO</name></author><id>tag:blog.picovico.com,2015-04-03:when-we-reached-50k-installs-of-picovico-slideshow-maker-on-android.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;On April 1, one of our friends leaked the news that we, along with another few, were being acquired by Google. You guessed it right- a prank obviously. But the write-up he put up in his blog actually made few people believe it and they ended up calling us asking about the valuation. Later, the same day, we ran the news that our Android app-&lt;a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.picovico.android"&gt;Picovico Slideshow Maker&lt;/a&gt; crossed the 50,000 installs mark on Play store. And as expected nobody believed it- thanks to the date again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Our free Android app that lets you make slideshows instantly has crossed 50K installs on Play Store." src="http://blog.picovico.com/theme/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/cover-50k.png" /&gt;
&lt;small&gt;Our free Android app that lets you make slideshows instantly has crossed 50K installs on Play Store.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But things happened a bit interestingly. We were monitoring the install stats and as soon as we realized the figure has crossed the 50K mark according to our calculations, we shared the news.  However what we missed was that to get this figure reflected in the Playstore it takes a little time. And whoever cross-checked the news thought that we were trying to fool them again. And the next day when things are reflected everywhere officially, they started congratulating us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, it took us some efforts to convince people around us about the news. April fool's day do backfire sometimes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyways on a little serious note, we would like to thank all our app users who tried our service and gave us constructive feedback along the way. Based on the latest ones, we're updating our app in 3 days with some new features and bug fixes. Do experience the &lt;a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.picovico.android&amp;amp;rdid=com.picovico.android"&gt;updated version&lt;/a&gt; and as always let us know how you feel about it. Your awesome pictures deserve a life, relive them with a #Picovico.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>How to create a slideshow video with music on Android?</title><link href="http://blog.picovico.com/how-to-create-a-photo-slideshow-video-with-music-on-android.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-03-06T06:34:21+05:45</updated><author><name>PICOVICO</name></author><id>tag:blog.picovico.com,2015-03-06:how-to-create-a-photo-slideshow-video-with-music-on-android.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;For those who are new to Picovico, let us tell you- creating a slideshow on Android device can be a daunting task if you are not using the right tool. But with Picovico's Android app, this experience can be pretty awesome to fall in love with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Picovico is made to let you make beautiful slideshow videos with ease. Our &lt;a href="http://picovico.com/android" target="_blank"&gt;Android app&lt;/a&gt; is so easy that in four steps you get your video ready to share. Wonder how? The process is explained here in a slideshare presentation with screenshots. Browse through and try creating one for yourself.
&lt;h3&gt;4 Steps to make a photo slideshow with music&lt;span style="font-size: 1.5em; font-weight: normal;"&gt;:
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
[caption id="attachment_800" align="aligncenter" width="432" caption="Click on the image"]&lt;a href="http://www.slideshare.net/picovico/how-to-create-a-free-video-slidshow-on-android-with-picovico"&gt;&lt;img class=" wp-image-800 " title="How to create a slideshow with music on android" src="theme/wp-content/uploads/2015/03/slideshare-thumbnail.jpg" alt="Photo slideshow with music on Android with Picovico" width="432" height="323" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;That was easy right? Now download the Picovico app from Playstore and get a hands-on experience of creating beautiful slideshow videos with music on Android- for free.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Behind the 'Blinds'</title><link href="http://blog.picovico.com/behind-the-blinds_slideshow-style.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-03-06T05:59:40+05:45</updated><author><name>PICOVICO</name></author><id>tag:blog.picovico.com,2015-03-06:behind-the-blinds_slideshow-style.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The latest addition in the collection of our video styles is (ta-da)- BLINDS.
&lt;div class="mceTemp mceIEcenter" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;dl id="attachment_794" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 422px;"&gt;&lt;dt class="wp-caption-dt"&gt;&lt;a href="theme/wp-content/uploads/2015/03/Blinds1.png"&gt;&lt;img class=" wp-image-794 " title="Blinds" src="theme/wp-content/uploads/2015/03/Blinds1.png" alt="Blinds Style" width="412" height="418" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd class="wp-caption-dd"&gt;Impressions unfolded with the Blinds&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;/dl&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
We just added Blinds to Picovico's public list of styles and that means you can now make videos using it. The style is inspired from the blinds curtains that we see at most of the workplaces. There is a lot to see behind those stripes-like things covering our windows and we want to you to look beyond and show it to the world. Since this style has simple effects and bold black/white colors, it makes a nice choice for business videos. Try it out today and if you want to share your work with us, simply mention @picovico on social platforms.  Meanwhile you may like to &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC0sFZ1KMw9yVvNbLh4NS_Bg?sub_confirmation=1" target="_blank"&gt;subscribe to our YouTube channel&lt;/a&gt; to watch a sample slideshow video in this style which we'll be adding soon.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="Slideshow Maker"></category><category term="style"></category><category term="Blinds"></category></entry><entry><title>What made 2014 your year awesome? Share with a Yearbook video!</title><link href="http://blog.picovico.com/share-moments-of-2014-with-a-yearbook-video-in-picovico.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-12-31T06:06:37+05:45</updated><author><name>PICOVICO</name></author><id>tag:blog.picovico.com,2014-12-31:share-moments-of-2014-with-a-yearbook-video-in-picovico.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Share the best moments of 2014 with a Yearbook video using Picovico&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="1093" caption="Picovico&amp;#39;s Yearbook Style to share best moments of the year that just passed."]&lt;img title="Picovico's Yearbook Style to share your best moments of the year that just passed. " src="theme/wp-content/uploads/2014/12/Yearbook-Screenshot.jpg" alt="Yearbook Style video slideshow in Picovico" width="1093" height="591" /&gt;[/caption]
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;After back to back release of two Christmas styles and a Winter Joy style, Picovico is releasing the Yearbook style on the occasion of New Year 2015.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;With this style you can share the best memories of the year 2014 and make a nice Picovico. Here is how you can do it: collect all your exciting and interesting pictures be they of your trips, parties, meetings, treks, graduation, marriage or sky dive. Put them all in order and add some interesting captions to each picture. Select the "Yearbook" style under Awesome tab in the app and finally choose a music from our library or upload your own track. Let Picovico do the rest of the magic.&lt;/p&gt;
In a couple of minutes, your video is ready to download in HD quality. Now share it on Facebook, Youtube or your favorite sites. Do not forget to mention @picovico if you want us to feature you on our official page. To watch one of the videos our user created in the Yearbook style, click &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/video.php?v=10155002915765596" target="_blank"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have not downloaded the app yet, download it for free from &lt;a href="http://goo.gl/gNiQDo" target="_blank"&gt;Playstore.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="Release"></category><category term="feature"></category><category term="yearbook"></category><category term="style"></category><category term="2015"></category></entry><entry><title>Let's Picovico this Christmas with beautiful videos!</title><link href="http://blog.picovico.com/lets-picovico-this-christmas.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-12-23T09:27:18+05:45</updated><author><name>PICOVICO</name></author><id>tag:blog.picovico.com,2014-12-23:lets-picovico-this-christmas.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Convert your Christmas celebration pictures into beautiful videos.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p align="justify"&gt;
&lt;img src="http://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/pv-styles/christmas/pv_christmas_winter_themes.png" alt="Picovico" /&gt;
We just launched two brand new video styles designed around Christmas theme. After days of designing, Picovico team brings you Christmas dedicated video styles so that you can share your pictures in an even attractive way this season.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The two themes are: Christmas Outdoor and Christmas Indoor and here is a glimpse of how they look.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://youtu.be/zn12LLgGmQc" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img src="theme/wp-content/uploads/2014/12/Christmas-Outdoor-Screenshot.jpg" title="Picovico Christmas Outdoor Style" alt="Picovico Outdoor Christmas Video Style" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="http://youtu.be/YQ-SOU7Ho44" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img src="theme/wp-content/uploads/2014/12/Christmas-Indoor-Screenshot.jpg" alt="Picovico Indoor Christmas Style Screenshot"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align="justify"&gt;You simply add your photos, choose one of these styles and create your video. Video quality ranges from 360p to HD and you can download the videos on your device to share anywhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align="justify"&gt;And interestingly, when you &lt;a href="http://goo.gl/VJbzuX"&gt;download the app&lt;/a&gt; and use one of these themes in a video within Dec 27, we can feature you on our facebook page and twitter profile. But do not forget to mention @picovico when you share the video on Facebook, Twitter or Youtube. So download the app today and gift someone a Picovico video this holiday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align="justify"&gt;If you want to watch some sample videos before you start creating your own, here is where you have to go: &lt;a href="http://goo.gl/CPrWpZ"&gt;Picovico on Youtube&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="picovico"></category><category term="christmas"></category><category term="themes"></category><category term="new themes"></category></entry><entry><title>Gift your loved ones a Picovico video this season!</title><link href="http://blog.picovico.com/gift-your-loved-ones-a-picovico-video-this-season.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-12-11T06:07:57+05:45</updated><author><name>PICOVICO</name></author><id>tag:blog.picovico.com,2014-12-11:gift-your-loved-ones-a-picovico-video-this-season.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;div&gt;

&lt;img id="headerImage campaign-icon" src="https://gallery.mailchimp.com/cb15b583ede89598802917646/images/52975b0c-fc4d-4b4d-a5c2-22dc66b2c28b.png" alt="Picovico_Convert_photos_into_videos" /&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Picovico 2.0 is here!&lt;/h1&gt;
Introducing you a completely revamped Android app.
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p align="justify"&gt;We are thrilled to release Picovico 2.0 for Android, the new and improved version of our popular app with the most requested features of all time! &lt;a href="http://goo.gl/VJbzuX"&gt;Update now&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Experience the new &lt;a href="http://goo.gl/YmFpWA" target="_blank"&gt;Picovico&lt;/a&gt;- completely re-imagined for mobile.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Enjoy smooth navigation and high-speed video rendering.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Download the video file on your device to share it anywhere.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;New theme comes preloaded into the app with regular updates.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
Creating videos on a mobile is easy and responsive using the power of our new video rendering engine. Try it now! You’ll love making videos with Picovico on Android. &lt;a href="http://picovico.com/app/#sample-videos"&gt;Watch Sample Video&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div id="magicdomid33" data-author-initials="y" data-author-link="/ep/profile/sDlIPpAkwuT" data-author-name="yogesh@picovico.com"&gt;
&lt;div&gt;

&lt;strong&gt;You get a premium style bundled with the app for free when you download the app within Dec 31.&lt;/strong&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="picovico"></category><category term="Holidays"></category><category term="android update"></category></entry><entry><title>Happy Father's Day</title><link href="http://blog.picovico.com/happy-fathers-day.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-06-12T18:36:54+05:45</updated><author><name>PICOVICO</name></author><id>tag:blog.picovico.com,2013-06-12:happy-fathers-day.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.picovico.com"&gt;&lt;img src="theme/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/cover-fathers-day-2013-2-copysd2.jpg" alt="Happy Father&amp;#039;s Day" title="Happy Father&amp;#039;s Day" width="851" height="315" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-670" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
A father’s love matter as much to a child as the &lt;a href="http://www.picovico.com/blog/make-this-mothers-day-more-special-with-picovico.html" title="Mother's Day" target="_blank"&gt;mother’s care&lt;/a&gt; does. We may call him dad, or old man, or simply father… we may call him by any name in our own dialects, and they all signify the special place he holds in our lives. He can be a daughter’s best buddy and a son’s real life hero. A mother’s care is always protective. She wants us to be forever careful for our own good. But a father’s care can be found to be quite the opposite. He wants us to try new things out, explore, learn by doing… and even if we fall, he will be right there to hold us up, and encourage us to try it out again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, a father may have flaws, like every human being does. But remember the time he was there holding the cycle while we tried our best to pedal is straight? Remember how he made us learn to respect our elders and to love and care for our friends and siblings? Remember how he would look out for us if someone was bullying us in the neighborhoods? And how he taught us to be able to stand on our own? We all have these special memories of our dads that make us smile time and again, that make us hold our heads high in pride, that can make us say that our dad is our hero.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us all show our gratitude to our dad on this father’s day. Let us thank him for the being the person that he is, for being the one who complete our families.
&lt;strong&gt;Happy Father’s Day!&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;object id="picovico-player-dc3a32760b9d476097848a615fb58d19" width="640" height="360" classid="clsid:d27cdb6e-ae6d-11cf-96b8-444553540000" codebase="http://download.macromedia.com/pub/shockwave/cabs/flash/swflash.cab#version=6,0,40,0"&gt;&lt;param name="allowfullscreen" value="true" /&gt;&lt;param name="allowscriptaccess" value="always" /&gt;&lt;param name="src" value="http://www.picovico.com/player/player.swf?file=http://s3.amazonaws.com/pvcdn2/video/dc3a32760b9d476097848a615fb58d19/dc3a32760b9d476097848a615fb58d19-360.mp4&amp;amp;image=http://s3.amazonaws.com/pvcdn2/video/dc3a32760b9d476097848a615fb58d19/dc3a32760b9d476097848a615fb58d19-360.jpg&amp;amp;skin=http://www.picovico.com//player/bekle.zip&amp;amp;baseurl=http://www.picovico.com/&amp;amp;controlbar.position=over&amp;amp;logo.file=http://www.picovico.com/themes/_global/images/picovico.png&amp;amp;logo.link=http://www.picovico.com/play/dc3a32760b9d476097848a615fb58d19&amp;amp;logo.margin=20&amp;amp;logo.position=top-left&amp;amp;logo.over=1&amp;amp;logo.out=0.8&amp;amp;logo.hide=false" /&gt;&lt;embed id="picovico-player-dc3a32760b9d476097848a615fb58d19" width="550" height="360" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" src="http://www.picovico.com/player/player.swf?file=http://s3.amazonaws.com/pvcdn2/video/dc3a32760b9d476097848a615fb58d19/dc3a32760b9d476097848a615fb58d19-360.mp4&amp;amp;image=http://s3.amazonaws.com/pvcdn2/video/dc3a32760b9d476097848a615fb58d19/dc3a32760b9d476097848a615fb58d19-360.jpg&amp;amp;skin=http://www.picovico.com//player/bekle.zip&amp;amp;baseurl=http://www.picovico.com/&amp;amp;controlbar.position=over&amp;amp;logo.file=http://www.picovico.com/themes/_global/images/picovico.png&amp;amp;logo.link=http://www.picovico.com/play/dc3a32760b9d476097848a615fb58d19&amp;amp;logo.margin=20&amp;amp;logo.position=top-left&amp;amp;logo.over=1&amp;amp;logo.out=0.8&amp;amp;logo.hide=false" allowfullscreen="true" allowscriptaccess="always" /&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="Photo-Video"></category><category term="Slideshow"></category><category term="Slideshow Maker"></category><category term="father"></category><category term="dad"></category><category term="parent"></category></entry><entry><title>Picovico gets featured in PandoDaily</title><link href="http://blog.picovico.com/picovico-gets-featured-in-pandodaily.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-05-27T08:46:08+05:45</updated><author><name>PICOVICO</name></author><id>tag:blog.picovico.com,2013-05-27:picovico-gets-featured-in-pandodaily.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;"They realized they had no option other than to try to provide something different. &lt;a href="theme/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/Untitled.png"&gt;&lt;img class="alignright  wp-image-638" title="Picovico" src="theme/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/Untitled.png" alt="" width="349" height="200" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; So Modi and Sapkota worked on making  the product as fast as possible, and have now got the video-rendering process down to 15 seconds for a 30-second video. Speed is now Picovico’s chief selling point."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read more about what Hamish Mckenzie, a reporter for PandoDaily said about &lt;a title="Picovico" href="http://picovico.com" target="_blank"&gt;Picovico&lt;/a&gt; in a special coverage by &lt;a title="Zippy Picovico attempts to take on Animoto from the mountains of Nepal" href="http://pandodaily.com/2013/05/23/zippy-picovico-attempts-to-take-on-animoto-from-the-mountains-of-nepal/"&gt;PandoDaily&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="Photo-Video"></category><category term="Slideshow"></category><category term="Slideshow Maker"></category></entry><entry><title>Google I/O 2013 Extended to be Held in Kathmandu</title><link href="http://blog.picovico.com/google-io-2013-extended-to-be-held-in-kathmandu.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-05-12T14:53:55+05:45</updated><author><name>PICOVICO</name></author><id>tag:blog.picovico.com,2013-05-12:google-io-2013-extended-to-be-held-in-kathmandu.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;a href="theme/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/google-io.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-599" title="google io" src="theme/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/google-io.jpg" alt="google io" width="851" height="315" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;Every year in San Francisco, Google organizes an event entirely focused on the developer. The event started in 2008 was named as &lt;strong&gt;Google I/O&lt;/strong&gt; where "I" and "O" stand for input/output, and &lt;em&gt;"Innovation in the Open"&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;a title="Google I/O" href="https://developers.google.com/events/io/" target="_blank"&gt;Google I/O&lt;/a&gt; features highly technical, in-depth sessions focused on building web, mobile, and enterprise applications with &lt;a title="Google" href="http://www.google.com" target="_blank"&gt;Google&lt;/a&gt; and open web technologies such as Android, Chrome, Chrome OS, Google APIs, Google Web Toolkit, App Engine, and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;The most exciting thing about this event is that, Google giveaways its latest gadgets in making to the attendees and this time the attendees are expecting to lay their hands on Google Glass. Amazingly, even the tickets gets sold out within minutes of its opening and this time It took only 49 minutes for all the $900 (or $300 for school students and faculty) tickets to get sold out, even with the added requirement that registrants must have both Google+ and Google Wallet accounts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;object id="picovico-player-5391ea3ae07f4ade98fd3502afa78440" width="550" height="360" classid="clsid:d27cdb6e-ae6d-11cf-96b8-444553540000" codebase="http://download.macromedia.com/pub/shockwave/cabs/flash/swflash.cab#version=6,0,40,0"&gt;&lt;param name="allowfullscreen" value="true" /&gt;&lt;param name="allowscriptaccess" value="always" /&gt;&lt;param name="src" value="http://www.picovico.com/player/player.swf?file=http://s3.amazonaws.com/pvcdn2/video/5391ea3ae07f4ade98fd3502afa78440/5391ea3ae07f4ade98fd3502afa78440-360.mp4&amp;amp;image=http://s3.amazonaws.com/pvcdn2/video/5391ea3ae07f4ade98fd3502afa78440/5391ea3ae07f4ade98fd3502afa78440-360.jpg&amp;amp;skin=http://www.picovico.com//player/bekle.zip&amp;amp;baseurl=http://www.picovico.com/&amp;amp;controlbar.position=over&amp;amp;logo.file=http://www.picovico.com/themes/_global/images/picovico.png&amp;amp;logo.link=http://www.picovico.com/play/5391ea3ae07f4ade98fd3502afa78440&amp;amp;logo.margin=20&amp;amp;logo.position=top-left&amp;amp;logo.over=1&amp;amp;logo.out=0.8&amp;amp;logo.hide=false" /&gt;&lt;embed id="picovico-player-5391ea3ae07f4ade98fd3502afa78440" width="550" height="360" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" src="http://www.picovico.com/player/player.swf?file=http://s3.amazonaws.com/pvcdn2/video/5391ea3ae07f4ade98fd3502afa78440/5391ea3ae07f4ade98fd3502afa78440-360.mp4&amp;amp;image=http://s3.amazonaws.com/pvcdn2/video/5391ea3ae07f4ade98fd3502afa78440/5391ea3ae07f4ade98fd3502afa78440-360.jpg&amp;amp;skin=http://www.picovico.com//player/bekle.zip&amp;amp;baseurl=http://www.picovico.com/&amp;amp;controlbar.position=over&amp;amp;logo.file=http://www.picovico.com/themes/_global/images/picovico.png&amp;amp;logo.link=http://www.picovico.com/play/5391ea3ae07f4ade98fd3502afa78440&amp;amp;logo.margin=20&amp;amp;logo.position=top-left&amp;amp;logo.over=1&amp;amp;logo.out=0.8&amp;amp;logo.hide=false" allowfullscreen="true" allowscriptaccess="always" /&gt;&lt;/object&gt;
&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;Google I/O event organized in countries outside USA is known by the name &lt;a title="Google I/O Extended" href="https://developers.google.com/events/io/io-extended" target="_blank"&gt;Google I/O Extended&lt;/a&gt;.  I/O Extended programming includes everything from live streaming the Google I/O content to local developer demos, hackathons, and speaker sessions. This year too, the Google I/O event is being organized at various locations across the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;In Nepal, the event is being organized by &lt;a title="Google Developers' Group" href="https://plus.google.com/104003514155874791868/posts" target="_blank"&gt;Google Developers’ Group&lt;/a&gt; with support from &lt;a title="Picovico" href="http://www.picovico.com" target="_blank"&gt;Picovico&lt;/a&gt; Inc. Google Developers’ Group is a local partner of Google in Nepal. It includes a group of developers and Google technology enthusiasts from around Kathmandu valley, Nepal, sharing  ideas, experiences and organizing various events and meetups. Picovico Inc, is a San Francisco based company originated in Nepal. Picovico, where pico stands for photos or pictures and vico stands for videos, is a tool for converting photos into video slideshows with music and texts co-created by Manish Modi and Suraj Sapkota.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;I/O Extended in Kathmandu will be held at Karkhana, Gyaneshwor, on 15th of May, from 8:30 pm on wards where developers from the valley will have an all night &lt;strong&gt;hackathon&lt;/strong&gt; and sessions where they will share ideas and experiences on &lt;strong&gt;technology&lt;/strong&gt; and hold discussion on &lt;strong&gt;current scenario in IT&lt;/strong&gt; sector in Nepal. Its an &lt;strong&gt;open event&lt;/strong&gt; so everybody is invited. Regular updates during the event could be obtained on Twitter via &lt;a title="#io13" href="https://twitter.com/search?q=%23io13&amp;amp;src=typd" target="_blank"&gt;#io13&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a title="#io13ktm" href="http://twitter.com/search/realtime?q=%23io13ktm&amp;amp;src=typd" target="_blank"&gt;#io13ktm&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: right;" dir="ltr"&gt;For more info SMS &lt;strong&gt;GoogleIO&lt;/strong&gt; to 4001&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary><category term="Google GoogleIO io13"></category></entry><entry><title>Make this Mother's Day a memorable one with an equally memorable video</title><link href="http://blog.picovico.com/make-this-mothers-day-more-special-with-picovico.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-05-05T20:50:17+05:45</updated><author><name>PICOVICO</name></author><id>tag:blog.picovico.com,2013-05-05:make-this-mothers-day-more-special-with-picovico.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p style="text-align: center;" dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;a href="theme/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/mothers-day-new-pic-widout-quote1.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-566" title="Mothers day" src="theme/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/mothers-day-new-pic-widout-quote1.jpg" alt="Mothers day" width="851" height="315" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;Every mother is so special, for reasons that we cannot count, for times that will keep on coming as long as we live, for she is the most beautiful blessing bestowed upon us. “Mom” always gives tender love, care and warmth. She teaches us the value of life; she makes us know what it means to love and to be loved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;Mom does a lot of things that we don’t even notice every day. She goes through our crazy tantrums and antics; she worries so  much even when we are just playing by the place next door. From broken dishes to bruised ankles, from our ever dramatic mood swings to out hurt crushing break ups, she is one person who always remains by our side, her warm hug ever ready to brighten our lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;We all have some wonderful memories that we cherish; those magic moments with our mothers we remember again and again. And now that the mother’s day is right around the corner, why not make it even more special this time around? How about &lt;a title="A gift for Mom" href="http://www.picovico.com/blog/a-gift-for-your-mom.html" target="_blank"&gt;dedicating a sweet video&lt;/a&gt; made out of those memorable pictures of you guys being together? And you don’t even need to plug on your laptop, all you need is those awesome pictures on your iPhone and &lt;a title="Picovico’s iPhone app" href="http://www.picovico.com/iphone" target="_blank"&gt;Picovico’s iPhone app&lt;/a&gt; installed in it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;Even better if you happen to go out on a shopping spree with your mom, or visit some fun place, or if you simply plan on staying at home and cook something delicious together with your mom. Why not snap some inside scoop, quickly make a video using the &lt;a title="picovico" href="http://picovico.com" target="_blank"&gt;Picovico&lt;/a&gt; iPhone app without letting her know and play it in front of her  to bring that look of awe and love and happiness, all at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;Rather than the monotonous slide of pictures, this allows you to choose a music or song of your choice that reflects the special moments you clicked together. And spice it up by adding texts to describe what those priceless moments mean to you. Now that makes up for a different yet awesome way to thank you mom for being the best mom in the world. A memorable mother’s day in an equally &lt;a title="The most unique Mother's Day gift" href="http://www.picovico.com/blog/the-most-unique-mothers-day-gift.html" target="_blank"&gt;memorable video&lt;/a&gt;, all within the touch of your fingers of  course!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;object id="picovico-player-e35830d2be2b462c91fc43b754187e6a" width="550" height="360" classid="clsid:d27cdb6e-ae6d-11cf-96b8-444553540000" codebase="http://download.macromedia.com/pub/shockwave/cabs/flash/swflash.cab#version=6,0,40,0"&gt;&lt;param name="allowfullscreen" value="true" /&gt;&lt;param name="allowscriptaccess" value="always" /&gt;&lt;param name="src" value="http://www.picovico.com/player/player.swf?file=http://s3.amazonaws.com/pvcdn2/video/e35830d2be2b462c91fc43b754187e6a/e35830d2be2b462c91fc43b754187e6a-360.mp4&amp;amp;image=http://s3.amazonaws.com/pvcdn2/video/e35830d2be2b462c91fc43b754187e6a/e35830d2be2b462c91fc43b754187e6a-360.jpg&amp;amp;skin=http://www.picovico.com//player/bekle.zip&amp;amp;baseurl=http://www.picovico.com/&amp;amp;controlbar.position=over&amp;amp;logo.file=http://www.picovico.com/themes/_global/images/picovico.png&amp;amp;logo.link=http://www.picovico.com/play/e35830d2be2b462c91fc43b754187e6a&amp;amp;logo.margin=20&amp;amp;logo.position=top-left&amp;amp;logo.over=1&amp;amp;logo.out=0.8&amp;amp;logo.hide=false" /&gt;&lt;embed id="picovico-player-e35830d2be2b462c91fc43b754187e6a" width="550" height="360" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" src="http://www.picovico.com/player/player.swf?file=http://s3.amazonaws.com/pvcdn2/video/e35830d2be2b462c91fc43b754187e6a/e35830d2be2b462c91fc43b754187e6a-360.mp4&amp;amp;image=http://s3.amazonaws.com/pvcdn2/video/e35830d2be2b462c91fc43b754187e6a/e35830d2be2b462c91fc43b754187e6a-360.jpg&amp;amp;skin=http://www.picovico.com//player/bekle.zip&amp;amp;baseurl=http://www.picovico.com/&amp;amp;controlbar.position=over&amp;amp;logo.file=http://www.picovico.com/themes/_global/images/picovico.png&amp;amp;logo.link=http://www.picovico.com/play/e35830d2be2b462c91fc43b754187e6a&amp;amp;logo.margin=20&amp;amp;logo.position=top-left&amp;amp;logo.over=1&amp;amp;logo.out=0.8&amp;amp;logo.hide=false" allowfullscreen="true" allowscriptaccess="always" /&gt;&lt;/object&gt;
&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;A very Happy Mother’s Day to you all!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary><category term="mother's day"></category><category term="gift"></category><category term="Photo-Video"></category><category term="Slideshow"></category><category term="Slideshow Maker"></category><category term="Mother"></category><category term="Photos to Videos"></category><category term="Special"></category></entry><entry><title>The Most Unique Mother's Day Gift</title><link href="http://blog.picovico.com/the-most-unique-mothers-day-gift.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-05-05T09:05:04+05:45</updated><author><name>PICOVICO</name></author><id>tag:blog.picovico.com,2013-05-05:the-most-unique-mothers-day-gift.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;a href="theme/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/comic_gift1.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-545" title="Same gift for mother's day" src="theme/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/comic_gift1.jpg" alt="Same gift for mother's day" width="832" height="426" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;Hah.. Hope this doesn't happen to you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;a title="Mother's Day" href="http://www.picovico.com/blog/make-this-mothers-day-more-special-with-picovico.html" target="_blank"&gt;Mother’s day&lt;/a&gt; is approaching and we all hope to bring the most unique &lt;a title="A Gift for your mom" href="http://www.picovico.com/blog/a-gift-for-your-mom.html" target="_blank"&gt;gift for our mothers&lt;/a&gt;. But it seems, things doesn't turn out as we think it to be. Why not try something at which we cannot fail. Infusing your gift with your personality will assure that, won’t it? Do something more thoughtful this time to make her feel special. &lt;a title="Create a video" href="http://www.picovico.com/iphone" target="_blank"&gt;Create&lt;/a&gt; a &lt;a title="How to create video using Picovico" href="http://www.picovico.com/blog/how-to-make-a-video.html" target="_blank"&gt;personalized video&lt;/a&gt; of you and your mother that no one else can make. Here are some video ideas to start with:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. She means the world to me&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nothing can compare to the love of your mother. Show her what she means to you and how you can’t imagine your world without her. Come up with a short and sweet poem and couple it with some beautiful pictures of you and her - laughing, hugging and having fun. Create a video of those special moments together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;object id="picovico-player-9381c658aea3421881cb2d124bf7b7a4" width="550" height="360" classid="clsid:d27cdb6e-ae6d-11cf-96b8-444553540000" codebase="http://download.macromedia.com/pub/shockwave/cabs/flash/swflash.cab#version=6,0,40,0"&gt;&lt;param name="allowfullscreen" value="true" /&gt;&lt;param name="allowscriptaccess" value="always" /&gt;&lt;param name="src" value="http://www.picovico.com/player/player.swf?file=http://s3.amazonaws.com/pvcdn2/video/9381c658aea3421881cb2d124bf7b7a4/9381c658aea3421881cb2d124bf7b7a4-360.mp4&amp;amp;image=http://s3.amazonaws.com/pvcdn2/video/9381c658aea3421881cb2d124bf7b7a4/9381c658aea3421881cb2d124bf7b7a4-360.jpg&amp;amp;skin=http://www.picovico.com//player/bekle.zip&amp;amp;baseurl=http://www.picovico.com/&amp;amp;controlbar.position=over&amp;amp;logo.file=http://www.picovico.com/themes/_global/images/picovico.png&amp;amp;logo.link=http://www.picovico.com/play/9381c658aea3421881cb2d124bf7b7a4&amp;amp;logo.margin=20&amp;amp;logo.position=top-left&amp;amp;logo.over=1&amp;amp;logo.out=0.8&amp;amp;logo.hide=false" /&gt;&lt;embed id="picovico-player-9381c658aea3421881cb2d124bf7b7a4" width="550" height="360" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" src="http://www.picovico.com/player/player.swf?file=http://s3.amazonaws.com/pvcdn2/video/9381c658aea3421881cb2d124bf7b7a4/9381c658aea3421881cb2d124bf7b7a4-360.mp4&amp;amp;image=http://s3.amazonaws.com/pvcdn2/video/9381c658aea3421881cb2d124bf7b7a4/9381c658aea3421881cb2d124bf7b7a4-360.jpg&amp;amp;skin=http://www.picovico.com//player/bekle.zip&amp;amp;baseurl=http://www.picovico.com/&amp;amp;controlbar.position=over&amp;amp;logo.file=http://www.picovico.com/themes/_global/images/picovico.png&amp;amp;logo.link=http://www.picovico.com/play/9381c658aea3421881cb2d124bf7b7a4&amp;amp;logo.margin=20&amp;amp;logo.position=top-left&amp;amp;logo.over=1&amp;amp;logo.out=0.8&amp;amp;logo.hide=false" allowfullscreen="true" allowscriptaccess="always" /&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. I am proud of her&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being a mother is no cake walk. She does all the super things that you can’t even imagine of. From giving you birth to taking care of you and the family. A friends, a guide, an inspiration - My mother. Create a video to show her how much you are proud of her and how beautifully she handles every hardship of life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;object id="picovico-player-f725c1ecaa2949b6b036928e9981cb9d" width="550" height="360" classid="clsid:d27cdb6e-ae6d-11cf-96b8-444553540000" codebase="http://download.macromedia.com/pub/shockwave/cabs/flash/swflash.cab#version=6,0,40,0"&gt;&lt;param name="allowfullscreen" value="true" /&gt;&lt;param name="allowscriptaccess" value="always" /&gt;&lt;param name="src" value="http://www.picovico.com/player/player.swf?file=http://s3.amazonaws.com/pvcdn2/video/f725c1ecaa2949b6b036928e9981cb9d/f725c1ecaa2949b6b036928e9981cb9d-360.mp4&amp;amp;image=http://s3.amazonaws.com/pvcdn2/video/f725c1ecaa2949b6b036928e9981cb9d/f725c1ecaa2949b6b036928e9981cb9d-360.jpg&amp;amp;skin=http://www.picovico.com//player/bekle.zip&amp;amp;baseurl=http://www.picovico.com/&amp;amp;controlbar.position=over&amp;amp;logo.file=http://www.picovico.com/themes/_global/images/picovico.png&amp;amp;logo.link=http://www.picovico.com/play/f725c1ecaa2949b6b036928e9981cb9d&amp;amp;logo.margin=20&amp;amp;logo.position=top-left&amp;amp;logo.over=1&amp;amp;logo.out=0.8&amp;amp;logo.hide=false" /&gt;&lt;embed id="picovico-player-f725c1ecaa2949b6b036928e9981cb9d" width="550" height="360" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" src="http://www.picovico.com/player/player.swf?file=http://s3.amazonaws.com/pvcdn2/video/f725c1ecaa2949b6b036928e9981cb9d/f725c1ecaa2949b6b036928e9981cb9d-360.mp4&amp;amp;image=http://s3.amazonaws.com/pvcdn2/video/f725c1ecaa2949b6b036928e9981cb9d/f725c1ecaa2949b6b036928e9981cb9d-360.jpg&amp;amp;skin=http://www.picovico.com//player/bekle.zip&amp;amp;baseurl=http://www.picovico.com/&amp;amp;controlbar.position=over&amp;amp;logo.file=http://www.picovico.com/themes/_global/images/picovico.png&amp;amp;logo.link=http://www.picovico.com/play/f725c1ecaa2949b6b036928e9981cb9d&amp;amp;logo.margin=20&amp;amp;logo.position=top-left&amp;amp;logo.over=1&amp;amp;logo.out=0.8&amp;amp;logo.hide=false" allowfullscreen="true" allowscriptaccess="always" /&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. A precious gift from God&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think of all the times your mom supported you. It could be your incomplete school lessons that she helped you complete or that art competition you had to win or your entire career she helped you get through. Whatever it was, but now its time you thank her for being there by your side. Collect pictures of all those times and make a video to show her how precious she is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;object id="picovico-player-1bb1d451b1044b1ba0955d5d40307ff7" width="550" height="360" classid="clsid:d27cdb6e-ae6d-11cf-96b8-444553540000" codebase="http://download.macromedia.com/pub/shockwave/cabs/flash/swflash.cab#version=6,0,40,0"&gt;&lt;param name="allowfullscreen" value="true" /&gt;&lt;param name="allowscriptaccess" value="always" /&gt;&lt;param name="src" value="http://www.picovico.com/player/player.swf?file=http://s3.amazonaws.com/pvcdn2/video/1bb1d451b1044b1ba0955d5d40307ff7/1bb1d451b1044b1ba0955d5d40307ff7-360.mp4&amp;amp;image=http://s3.amazonaws.com/pvcdn2/video/1bb1d451b1044b1ba0955d5d40307ff7/1bb1d451b1044b1ba0955d5d40307ff7-360.jpg&amp;amp;skin=http://www.picovico.com//player/bekle.zip&amp;amp;baseurl=http://www.picovico.com/&amp;amp;controlbar.position=over&amp;amp;logo.file=http://www.picovico.com/themes/_global/images/picovico.png&amp;amp;logo.link=http://www.picovico.com/play/1bb1d451b1044b1ba0955d5d40307ff7&amp;amp;logo.margin=20&amp;amp;logo.position=top-left&amp;amp;logo.over=1&amp;amp;logo.out=0.8&amp;amp;logo.hide=false" /&gt;&lt;embed id="picovico-player-1bb1d451b1044b1ba0955d5d40307ff7" width="550" height="360" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" src="http://www.picovico.com/player/player.swf?file=http://s3.amazonaws.com/pvcdn2/video/1bb1d451b1044b1ba0955d5d40307ff7/1bb1d451b1044b1ba0955d5d40307ff7-360.mp4&amp;amp;image=http://s3.amazonaws.com/pvcdn2/video/1bb1d451b1044b1ba0955d5d40307ff7/1bb1d451b1044b1ba0955d5d40307ff7-360.jpg&amp;amp;skin=http://www.picovico.com//player/bekle.zip&amp;amp;baseurl=http://www.picovico.com/&amp;amp;controlbar.position=over&amp;amp;logo.file=http://www.picovico.com/themes/_global/images/picovico.png&amp;amp;logo.link=http://www.picovico.com/play/1bb1d451b1044b1ba0955d5d40307ff7&amp;amp;logo.margin=20&amp;amp;logo.position=top-left&amp;amp;logo.over=1&amp;amp;logo.out=0.8&amp;amp;logo.hide=false" allowfullscreen="true" allowscriptaccess="always" /&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong id="docs-internal-guid--425b9d0-7386-aa7a-8a67-04221c4f588e"&gt; So, What story are you thinking of now?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="mother's day"></category><category term="gift"></category><category term="Photo-Video"></category><category term="Slideshow"></category><category term="Slideshow Maker"></category><category term="Mother"></category><category term="Photos to Videos"></category><category term="Special"></category></entry><entry><title>Picovico at the Global Entrepreneurship Congress 2013</title><link href="http://blog.picovico.com/picovico-at-the-global-entrepreneurship-congress-2013.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-03-20T09:20:09+05:45</updated><author><name>PICOVICO</name></author><id>tag:blog.picovico.com,2013-03-20:picovico-at-the-global-entrepreneurship-congress-2013.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;a href="theme/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/testa-site_ENG.gif"&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-461" title="testa site_ENG" src="theme/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/testa-site_ENG.gif" alt="Global Entrepreneurship Congress 2013" width="966" height="227" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I&lt;/strong&gt;nitiated in United States by&lt;a href="http://www.kauffman.org/" target="_blank"&gt; Ewing Marion Kauffman Foundation&lt;/a&gt; in March 2009 by bringing together host organizations from about 60 countries, &lt;a title="Global Entrepreneurship congress 2013" href="http://gec2013.com/en" target="_blank"&gt;Global Entrepreneurship Congress 2013&lt;/a&gt; is a congregation of innovative minds from various startups ranging across number of disciplines. The event brings together entrepreneurs, investors, researchers, thought leaders and policymakers with the purpose of sharing of ideas, help metamorphose them into reality, advance economic growth and also to celebrate the inspirations and dreams that drive every successful entrepreneur.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being organized in different parts of the world since past four years, this year GEC is being held in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil from 18 to 21 March, 2013. The core sessions of the event are being held at the Rodrigo de Freitas Lagoon while the fringe events will be held at different venues across the city of Rio. The congress this year intends on bringing the policymakers and startups together in order to forge a better understanding between the two and build an environment more favorable and hopeful for the startups and new firms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="theme/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/GEC2013_entreps_slider_nore.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-464" title="GEC2013_entreps_slider_nore" src="theme/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/GEC2013_entreps_slider_nore.jpg" alt="Global entrepreneurship congress 2013" width="1100" height="400" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hosted by Global Entrepreneurship Week, the Kauffman Foundation and &lt;a href="http://www.endeavor.org.br/" target="_blank"&gt;Endeavor Brasil&lt;/a&gt; and supported by &lt;a title="Dell" href="http://www.dell.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Dell&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.nyx.com/nyse-euronext-foundation" target="_blank"&gt;NYSE Euronext Foundation&lt;/a&gt;, the attendees in the congress will be hearing from over fifty speakers that include names like&lt;a href="http://www.feld.com/wp/about" target="_blank"&gt; Brad Feld &lt;/a&gt;- Co-founder, &lt;a href="http://www.techstars.com/" target="_blank"&gt;TechStars&lt;/a&gt;, United States;&lt;a href="http://www.thegazellegroup.com/fintan-donohue-gp.php" target="_blank"&gt; Fintan Donohue &lt;/a&gt;- CEO, &lt;a href="http://www.gazellegroup.com/home/" target="_blank"&gt;Gazelle Group&lt;/a&gt;, United Kingdom; &lt;a href="http://500.co/mentors/dave-mcclure-2/" target="_blank"&gt;Dave McClure&lt;/a&gt; - Founding Partner, &lt;a title="500 Startups" href="http://500.co/" target="_blank"&gt;500 Startups&lt;/a&gt;;  &lt;a title="Bowei Gai" href="http://www.linkedin.com/in/boweigai" target="_blank"&gt;Bowei Gai&lt;/a&gt; - Founder - &lt;a href="http://www.worldstartupreport.com/" target="_blank"&gt;World Startup Report &lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a title="Lesa Mitchell" href="http://www.linkedin.com/in/lesamitchell" target="_blank"&gt;Lesa Mitchell&lt;/a&gt; - Vice President of Innovation and Networks, &lt;a title="Kauffman Foundation" href="http://www.kauffman.org/" target="_blank"&gt;Kauffman Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With delegates from over hundred countries with varied economies and socio-political and cultural background, the Global Entrepreneurship congress 2013 focuses on awareness and celebration, experiential education, financing growth, smart government policies and strategies for progress and empowerment of both the startups and national and international economy. Suraj Sapkota from Chile will be representing Picovico Inc, a San Francisco based company originated in Nepal, at the congress. &lt;a href="http://www.picovico.com" target="_blank"&gt;Picovico&lt;/a&gt;, where pico stands for photos or pictures and vico stands for videos, is a tool for converting photos into a slideshow with music and texts co-created by Manish Modi and Suraj Sapkota.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/5F63y5OsdDY?rel=0" frameborder="0" width="520" height="330"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every photo clicked has a story behind it, with an aim to facilitate the act of photo sharing keeping the story associated with each snap intact and to make the art of storytelling more appealing, the two engineers from Nepal Manish Modi and Suraj Sapkota came up with this idea of creating a free web based tool. The duo was supported in their endeavor by Morpheus, a startup accelerator, and later the startup was included in &lt;a href="http://www.picovico.com/blog/picovico-is-now-a-part-of-start-up-chile.html" target="_blank"&gt;Start-up Chile program&lt;/a&gt;. The tool is &lt;a href="http://www.picovico.com/blog/how-to-make-a-video.html" target="_blank"&gt;easy to use&lt;/a&gt; and allows you choose from wide range of styles. You can add photos from your computer or import from Facebook or Flickr, add text to each photo, add music of your choice or from the available list of music and title and short description to the video. Thus created video can be downloaded, burnt on a DVD, and even used in &lt;a href="http://www.picovico.com/blog/picovico-video-presentation-tools.html" target="_blank"&gt;powerpoint presentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, if you have snaps with an interesting story behind them, go Picovico!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="Photo-Video"></category><category term="Slideshow"></category><category term="Slideshow Maker"></category><category term="gec2013"></category><category term="innovation"></category></entry><entry><title>Celebrate St. Patrick's Day with Picovico</title><link href="http://blog.picovico.com/celebrate-st-patricks-day-with-picovico.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-03-16T10:28:00+05:45</updated><author><name>PICOVICO</name></author><id>tag:blog.picovico.com,2013-03-16:celebrate-st-patricks-day-with-picovico.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="theme/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Patricks-day_picovico.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-445" title="Patricks day_picovico" src="theme/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Patricks-day_picovico.jpg" alt="St. Patrick's day" width="751" height="250" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;W&lt;/strong&gt;hat comes to your mind when we say “St. Patrick’s Day”? - The color green, gold, shamrocks and luck. Dance, music, Irish food and drinks; whatever you do on this day must be fun. Green-gold is the theme, so go green otherwise you will be pinched ;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Memories of getting drunk, trying Irish food, dancing to a local Irish song, and making friends during celebration lasts for a lifetime. Obviously, you gotta capture those moments and converting them into a video would be a good idea. Don’t you think so? Well, we think its perfect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rather than going through the album, you can just play a video to relive those times. And to convert those pictures into a fine video; what better tool can you find than&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a title="Picovico" href="http://www.picovico.com" target="_blank"&gt; Picovico&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;a title="Slideshow maker " href="http://www.picovico.com/blog/how-to-make-a-video.html" target="_blank"&gt;Making video&lt;/a&gt; with Picovico is a fun process. Just upload your favorite pictures from the day, choose a theme and make it exciting by adding your favorite Irish song in the background. This video will always refresh the memories of the day. Here's the one we made from last year:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/8hX5nvVktxo?rel=0" frameborder="0" width="510" height="315"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what are you waiting for? Go out, have fun, be a green maniac and earn some luck. At the end don’t forget to share that memorable video with us, the happy feel of the whole day’s celebration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happy St. Patrick's Day from Picovico! :)&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="Photo-Video"></category><category term="Slideshow"></category><category term="Slideshow Maker"></category><category term="patrick"></category><category term="fun"></category><category term="parade"></category></entry><entry><title>Picovico Videos as Strong Presentation Tools</title><link href="http://blog.picovico.com/picovico-video-presentation-tools.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-03-01T18:35:42+05:45</updated><author><name>PICOVICO</name></author><id>tag:blog.picovico.com,2013-03-01:picovico-video-presentation-tools.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="theme/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/powerpoint_video.png"&gt;&lt;img class="wp-image-379 alignleft" title="powerpoint_video" src="theme/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/powerpoint_video.png" alt="Powerpoint Video" width="149" height="95" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;P&lt;/strong&gt;owerpoint presentation tools is taken as an effective tool for presenting your ideas. Its convenient and easy to use too. But then, sometimes it gets so boring with the use of just  bullets and pointers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How about adding a video to your presentation. Its a great presentation tools to grab attention and also a good place to include lots of pictures. You can use videos from &lt;a title="Picovico" href="http://www.picovico.com" target="_blank"&gt;Picovico&lt;/a&gt; to add in that extra special finishing touch to your regular presentations. Some of the greatest  advantages of using Picovico videos is that its &lt;a href="http://www.picovico.com/blog/how-to-make-a-video.html" target="_blank"&gt;easy to make&lt;/a&gt; and download absolutely free of cost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So here’s how you can embed videos from Picovico:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Download:
&lt;/strong&gt;You can download your videos from your Picovico account directly into mp4 format to your computer. Open the video you want to download and goto “Video Settings” just above the video screen. Click on “Download” and save the video on your computer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="theme/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/picovico_download.png"&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-373" title="picovico_download" src="theme/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/picovico_download.png" alt="" width="851" height="539" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;strong&gt;2. Inserting videos into PowerPoint:&lt;/strong&gt;
After you have downloaded the video you want to insert it in your presentation, open your presentation file. Then go to “Insert” tab in the menu bar. There you will find “Movie” at the right end. Choose the “movie from file” option and insert your previously downloaded video from Picovico.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter" src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/7bml2nb8_w4vxIKbMmgmn62ESepuASdtHUgKo7IO3_vyjVnaSbgmUUZSnwNOPq9uYM4Oztjo_Bq2Hikf3Z5v12sxqIaVYs7gjmuATHm-jh3bJpeZqBv4jmfVeToj9B2c2Q" alt="" width="624px;" height="110px;" /&gt;
Picovico videos can prove as one of the strong presentation tools. Addition of a simple video to a good presentation will surely make it a better one. Now, go on and dazzle your audiences with your presentation.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="Photo-Video"></category><category term="Slideshow"></category><category term="Slideshow Maker"></category><category term="powerpoint"></category><category term="presentation"></category><category term="slides"></category></entry><entry><title>How to make a video using Picovico</title><link href="http://blog.picovico.com/how-to-make-a-video.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-02-24T14:49:40+05:45</updated><author><name>PICOVICO</name></author><id>tag:blog.picovico.com,2013-02-24:how-to-make-a-video.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;a href="theme/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/Picovico_How-to1.png"&gt;&lt;img class=" wp-image-326 aligncenter" title="Picovico_How to" src="theme/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/Picovico_How-to1.png" alt="how to make video " width="646" height="217" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;O&lt;/strong&gt;ne always loves to click or get clicked, and at the end of the day when we look behind we are left with a set of photos as a reservoir of our memories. But have we ever felt that these captured moments are actually missing their livelihood? As by simply seeing those pictures one can’t get a clear picture of the story behind it. And here comes &lt;a title="Picovico" href="http://www.picovico.com" target="_blank"&gt;Picovico&lt;/a&gt;; a perfect solution to relive your moments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Picovico is a web based video slideshow maker that can make your pictures look tremendously better with added music and special effects. It makes it easy for you to create a video with no registry hassle and no cost. Go to www.picovico.com and login with you Facebook account or use your email to get an account on Picovico.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here is how to make a video using Picovico:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(1) Select a style:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enhance your legendary pictures with different styles. Picovico gives you a choice of  Video styles to set the mood. Want to put together pictures to the tunes of your favorite song? We got a style to go with that.
&lt;p style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;a href="theme/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/how-to-make-a-video_1.png"&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-333" style="border: 1px solid black;" title="how to make a video_1" src="theme/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/how-to-make-a-video_1.png" alt="how to make a video" width="669" height="494" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;(2) Upload your photos:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can &lt;a href="http://www.picovico.com/blog/10000-photos-upload.html" target="_blank"&gt;upload&lt;/a&gt; your photos from computer or import from Facebook or Flickr. Then you can add captions to uploaded photos or add new text slides along with it.
&lt;p style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;a href="theme/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/how-to-make-a-video_2.png"&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-334" style="border: 1px solid black;" title="how to make a video_2" src="theme/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/how-to-make-a-video_2.png" alt="how to make a video" width="719" height="360" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;(3) Choose your music:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A wide variety of music (instrumentals) is made available for you to select from. Don't like instrumentals? You can upload your own music too.
&lt;p style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;a href="theme/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/how-to-make-a-video_3.png"&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-335" style="border: 1px solid black;" title="how to make a video_3" src="theme/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/how-to-make-a-video_3.png" alt="how to make a video_1" width="721" height="500" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;(4) Personalize your video:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Give your video a beautiful title, choose options for sharing and press the RED BUTTON. Picovico will turn your photos into a spiffy video and notify you by email when done.
&lt;p style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;a href="theme/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/how-to-make-a-video_4.png"&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-336" style="border: 1px solid black;" title="how to make a video_4" src="theme/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/how-to-make-a-video_4.png" alt="" width="719" height="406" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
Now you can leave your freshly minted video of awesomeness on site for &lt;a href="http://www.picovico.com/en/video/timeline" target="_blank"&gt;public viewing&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="http://www.picovico.com/blog/let-your-video-go-social.html" target="_blank"&gt;share&lt;/a&gt; it on Facebook or YouTube or embed it on your website or blog. You can also download and save a copy on your desktop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.picovico.com/en/play/c707852a79ee474d9465f14328ddcd24"&gt;&lt;object id="picovico-player-c707852a79ee474d9465f14328ddcd24" width="515" height="360" classid="clsid:d27cdb6e-ae6d-11cf-96b8-444553540000" codebase="http://download.macromedia.com/pub/shockwave/cabs/flash/swflash.cab#version=6,0,40,0"&gt;&lt;param name="allowfullscreen" value="true" /&gt;&lt;param name="allowscriptaccess" value="always" /&gt;&lt;param name="src" value="http://www.picovico.com/player/player.swf?file=http://s3.amazonaws.com/pvcdn2/video/c707852a79ee474d9465f14328ddcd24/c707852a79ee474d9465f14328ddcd24-360.mp4&amp;amp;image=http://s3.amazonaws.com/pvcdn2/video/c707852a79ee474d9465f14328ddcd24/c707852a79ee474d9465f14328ddcd24-360.jpg&amp;amp;skin=http://www.picovico.com//player/bekle.zip&amp;amp;baseurl=http://www.picovico.com/&amp;amp;controlbar.position=over&amp;amp;logo.file=http://www.picovico.com/themes/_global/images/picovico.png&amp;amp;logo.link=http://www.picovico.com/play/c707852a79ee474d9465f14328ddcd24&amp;amp;logo.margin=20&amp;amp;logo.position=top-left&amp;amp;logo.over=1&amp;amp;logo.out=0.8&amp;amp;logo.hide=false" /&gt;&lt;embed id="picovico-player-c707852a79ee474d9465f14328ddcd24" width="515" height="360" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" src="http://www.picovico.com/player/player.swf?file=http://s3.amazonaws.com/pvcdn2/video/c707852a79ee474d9465f14328ddcd24/c707852a79ee474d9465f14328ddcd24-360.mp4&amp;amp;image=http://s3.amazonaws.com/pvcdn2/video/c707852a79ee474d9465f14328ddcd24/c707852a79ee474d9465f14328ddcd24-360.jpg&amp;amp;skin=http://www.picovico.com//player/bekle.zip&amp;amp;baseurl=http://www.picovico.com/&amp;amp;controlbar.position=over&amp;amp;logo.file=http://www.picovico.com/themes/_global/images/picovico.png&amp;amp;logo.link=http://www.picovico.com/play/c707852a79ee474d9465f14328ddcd24&amp;amp;logo.margin=20&amp;amp;logo.position=top-left&amp;amp;logo.over=1&amp;amp;logo.out=0.8&amp;amp;logo.hide=false" allowfullscreen="true" allowscriptaccess="always" /&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Its all about stimulating multiple senses of your viewers i.e., looking beautiful to the eyes &amp;amp; sounding good to the ears and Picovico lets you do that! It lets you make videos that keep viewers entertained through countless photos and &lt;a href="http://www.picovico.com/blog/have-a-story-express.html" target="_blank"&gt;express your story&lt;/a&gt; at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use Picovico to make videos that people will actually want to watch!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="video"></category><category term="Slideshow Maker"></category><category term="how-to"></category><category term="video-making"></category></entry><entry><title>This Valentine's Day Say It The Picovico Way</title><link href="http://blog.picovico.com/this-valentines-day-say-it-the-picovico-way.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-02-12T18:44:09+05:45</updated><author><name>PICOVICO</name></author><id>tag:blog.picovico.com,2013-02-12:this-valentines-day-say-it-the-picovico-way.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="theme/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/Picovico_valentine0.png"&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-279" title="Picovico_valentine0" src="theme/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/Picovico_valentine0.png" alt="valentine gifts " width="826" height="278" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have you thought about what your gift is going to be for your beloved one this Valentine’s day?
Are chocolates, teddy bears and roses going to be enough? This could be very well be a big question mark for most of us! You try and want to be different every time on such occasions, anxious enough to look out for that special way to impress your someone special. Nevertheless, it ends up with same ol' regular ways of presenting the regular gifts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have you ever thought of using a picture slideshow as a gift to express your true feelings for the special one? Yes, right! &lt;a title="Picovico" href="http://www.picovico.com"&gt;Picovico&lt;/a&gt; gives you an opportunity to express your love the coolest way this Valentine’s day. Its fast, its easy and its Personal!. Picovico is free online software to turn your beautiful pictures into awesome videos. Materials that you will require to make a perfect &lt;strong&gt;Gift Video&lt;/strong&gt; are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Set of photographs:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;Everyone always have a set of photographs of their loved ones with them and few more pictures of hearts, flowers, and candles with romantic lines. And you are ready with first of requirement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;a href="theme/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/11.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-290" title="Picovico_Valentine_1" src="theme/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/11.jpg" alt="valentine's day" width="697" height="345" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. A story line:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;a href="theme/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/21.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="theme/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/21.jpg" alt="valentines day" title="Picovico_Valentine_2" width="359" height="285" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-319" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;a href="theme/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/3.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-293" title="Picovico_Valentine_3" src="theme/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/3.jpg" alt="valentine's day" width="700" height="393" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;After you have sorted the pictures you can create a story line, may be something romantic. For example if you are proposing in Valentine’s day, write something special and romantic and the very end you can express you love with “I love you”, at the end. You can send in messages with it like”will you be my Valentine?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;3. Music:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;a href="theme/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/42.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="theme/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/42.jpg" alt="valentines day" title="Picovico_Valentine_4" width="462" height="393" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-321" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
Who does not love music? Is that even a question? Everybody has their favorite. You can add music from the already available Picovico music library or you can import your own songs or instrumentals that your beloved one loves to listen. Music helps to set the feel of the video and makes it quite effective than just a set of pictures put together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now be ready to prepare an awesome gift for the Valentine’s Day. Picovico allows you to choose the theme for your video, arrange the sorted pictures, and then add the music. A good setting of course helps you to convey you message, don’t let the environment disturb you and your loved one (deciding the right time and place to play it remain in our hand). Here is the one we made:
&lt;object id="picovico-player-896a76d9b2cb4b61990f66ea0ccb003e" width="550" height="360" classid="clsid:d27cdb6e-ae6d-11cf-96b8-444553540000" codebase="http://download.macromedia.com/pub/shockwave/cabs/flash/swflash.cab#version=6,0,40,0"&gt;&lt;param name="allowfullscreen" value="true" /&gt;&lt;param name="allowscriptaccess" value="always" /&gt;&lt;param name="src" value="http://www.picovico.com/player/player.swf?file=http://s3.amazonaws.com/pvcdn2/video/896a76d9b2cb4b61990f66ea0ccb003e/896a76d9b2cb4b61990f66ea0ccb003e-360.mp4&amp;amp;image=http://s3.amazonaws.com/pvcdn2/video/896a76d9b2cb4b61990f66ea0ccb003e/896a76d9b2cb4b61990f66ea0ccb003e-360.jpg&amp;amp;skin=http://www.picovico.com//player/bekle.zip&amp;amp;baseurl=http://www.picovico.com/&amp;amp;controlbar.position=over&amp;amp;logo.file=http://www.picovico.com/themes/_global/images/picovico.png&amp;amp;logo.link=http://www.picovico.com/play/896a76d9b2cb4b61990f66ea0ccb003e&amp;amp;logo.margin=20&amp;amp;logo.position=top-left&amp;amp;logo.over=1&amp;amp;logo.out=0.8&amp;amp;logo.hide=false" /&gt;&lt;embed id="picovico-player-896a76d9b2cb4b61990f66ea0ccb003e" width="550" height="360" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" src="http://www.picovico.com/player/player.swf?file=http://s3.amazonaws.com/pvcdn2/video/896a76d9b2cb4b61990f66ea0ccb003e/896a76d9b2cb4b61990f66ea0ccb003e-360.mp4&amp;amp;image=http://s3.amazonaws.com/pvcdn2/video/896a76d9b2cb4b61990f66ea0ccb003e/896a76d9b2cb4b61990f66ea0ccb003e-360.jpg&amp;amp;skin=http://www.picovico.com//player/bekle.zip&amp;amp;baseurl=http://www.picovico.com/&amp;amp;controlbar.position=over&amp;amp;logo.file=http://www.picovico.com/themes/_global/images/picovico.png&amp;amp;logo.link=http://www.picovico.com/play/896a76d9b2cb4b61990f66ea0ccb003e&amp;amp;logo.margin=20&amp;amp;logo.position=top-left&amp;amp;logo.over=1&amp;amp;logo.out=0.8&amp;amp;logo.hide=false" allowfullscreen="true" allowscriptaccess="always" /&gt;&lt;/object&gt;
Don’t waste your time thinking for anything extra this valentine’s day, just go for Picovico. Celebrate this Valentine's Day the PV way!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="Slideshow"></category><category term="Valentine"></category><category term="Love"></category><category term="Celebration"></category><category term="Slideshow Maker"></category><category term="February"></category></entry><entry><title>Merry Christmas and Happy Holidays!!!</title><link href="http://blog.picovico.com/merry-christmas-and-happy-holidays.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-12-25T22:31:06+05:45</updated><author><name>PICOVICO</name></author><id>tag:blog.picovico.com,2012-12-25:merry-christmas-and-happy-holidays.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;"Christmas waves a magic wand over this world, and behold, everything is softer and more beautiful.”  ~ Norman Vincent Peale&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The yuletide season has begun and the air is filled with Christmas and celebrations. It’s the season of holidays, parties, hangouts, exchanging gifts. And before you get dissolved in this celebratory air, we at Picovico wanna thank you for being with us in the journey, with all the highs and lows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;embed allowfullscreen="true" allowscriptaccess="always" id="picovico-player-8a4bb62006b945bdad299d74136a0225" name="picovico-player-8a4bb62006b945bdad299d74136a0225" src="https://www.picovico.com/player/player.swf?file=http://s3.amazonaws.com/pvcdn2/video/8a4bb62006b945bdad299d74136a0225/8a4bb62006b945bdad299d74136a0225-360.mp4&amp;image=http://s3.amazonaws.com/pvcdn2/video/8a4bb62006b945bdad299d74136a0225/8a4bb62006b945bdad299d74136a0225-360.jpg&amp;skin=https://www.picovico.com//player/bekle.zip&amp;baseurl=https://www.picovico.com/&amp;controlbar.position=over&amp;logo.file=https://www.picovico.com/themes/_global/images/picovico.png&amp;logo.link=https://www.picovico.com/play/8a4bb62006b945bdad299d74136a0225&amp;logo.margin=20&amp;logo.position=top-left&amp;logo.over=1&amp;logo.out=0.8&amp;logo.hide=false" width="550" height="350"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wish you a Merry Christmas and Happy Holidays!!
&lt;blockquote&gt;“Live your moments and Freeze them.
With Picovico, give it Life and Relive them.”&lt;/blockquote&gt;
And, don’t forget to share your magic moments with your friends.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="photos"></category><category term="memories"></category><category term="Photo-Video"></category><category term="Slideshow"></category><category term="Merry Christmas"></category><category term="Holidays"></category><category term="Christmas Celebration"></category></entry><entry><title>Picovico now available in Espanol and Japanese.</title><link href="http://blog.picovico.com/picovico-speaks-espanol-and-japanese.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-12-15T09:47:04+05:45</updated><author><name>PICOVICO</name></author><id>tag:blog.picovico.com,2012-12-15:picovico-speaks-espanol-and-japanese.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title="Picovico - Slideshow Maker" href="http://www.picovico.com" target="_blank"&gt;Picovico&lt;/a&gt; is all about &lt;a href="http://www.picovico.com/blog/have-a-story-express.html" target="_blank"&gt;Expression&lt;/a&gt; and in what language can you express better than your own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Picovico had moved to Santiago &lt;a title="Picovico Startup Chile Program" href="http://www.picovico.com/blog/picovico-is-now-a-part-of-start-up-chile.html" target="_blank"&gt;as a part of Startup Chile&lt;/a&gt; 2 months ago with bigger dreams and hopes. And we were overwhelmed by the exquisite beauty of this place and people around, the moment we arrived. We see that everyone here cherish the beauty of their country, love taking photos and  Bingo! As we expected, Picovico could stand as the best medium for them to share those photos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;object id="picovico-player-ebd1511ee3a0410c8005016f484b2c37" width="550" height="310" classid="clsid:d27cdb6e-ae6d-11cf-96b8-444553540000" codebase="http://download.macromedia.com/pub/shockwave/cabs/flash/swflash.cab#version=6,0,40,0"&gt;&lt;param name="allowfullscreen" value="true" /&gt;&lt;param name="allowscriptaccess" value="always" /&gt;&lt;param name="src" value="https://www.picovico.com/player/player.swf?file=http://s3.amazonaws.com/pvcdn2/video/ebd1511ee3a0410c8005016f484b2c37/ebd1511ee3a0410c8005016f484b2c37-360.mp4&amp;amp;image=http://s3.amazonaws.com/pvcdn2/video/ebd1511ee3a0410c8005016f484b2c37/ebd1511ee3a0410c8005016f484b2c37-360.jpg&amp;amp;skin=https://www.picovico.com//player/bekle.zip&amp;amp;baseurl=https://www.picovico.com/&amp;amp;controlbar.position=over&amp;amp;logo.file=https://www.picovico.com/themes/_global/images/picovico.png&amp;amp;logo.link=https://www.picovico.com/play/ebd1511ee3a0410c8005016f484b2c37&amp;amp;logo.margin=20&amp;amp;logo.position=top-left&amp;amp;logo.over=1&amp;amp;logo.out=0.8&amp;amp;logo.hide=false" /&gt;&lt;embed id="picovico-player-ebd1511ee3a0410c8005016f484b2c37" width="550" height="310" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" src="https://www.picovico.com/player/player.swf?file=http://s3.amazonaws.com/pvcdn2/video/ebd1511ee3a0410c8005016f484b2c37/ebd1511ee3a0410c8005016f484b2c37-360.mp4&amp;amp;image=http://s3.amazonaws.com/pvcdn2/video/ebd1511ee3a0410c8005016f484b2c37/ebd1511ee3a0410c8005016f484b2c37-360.jpg&amp;amp;skin=https://www.picovico.com//player/bekle.zip&amp;amp;baseurl=https://www.picovico.com/&amp;amp;controlbar.position=over&amp;amp;logo.file=https://www.picovico.com/themes/_global/images/picovico.png&amp;amp;logo.link=https://www.picovico.com/play/ebd1511ee3a0410c8005016f484b2c37&amp;amp;logo.margin=20&amp;amp;logo.position=top-left&amp;amp;logo.over=1&amp;amp;logo.out=0.8&amp;amp;logo.hide=false" allowfullscreen="true" allowscriptaccess="always" /&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, there was a language barrier as the native language here is Spanish and Picovico was available in English only. We thought, people might not relate with it so well (adding more to the reason is the literal meaning of "Pico" in Spanish! :P ). So, the good news; We launched an exclusive website "&lt;a href="http://www.picvic.cl/en/home" target="_blank"&gt;picvic.cl&lt;/a&gt;" for Chile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, when we started with one language, we got a hang of this idea of making Picovico available for all the countries in their native languages. How cool it would be to have a personalized video and that too in your own language. Japanese was just to start with!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this Picovico is now available in 3 languages (&lt;a title="Picovico in English" href="http://www.picovico.com/en/home" target="_blank"&gt;English&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a title="Picovico in Spanish" href="http://www.picovico.com/es/home" target="_blank"&gt;Spanish&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a title="Picovico in Japanese" href="http://www.picovico.com/jp/home" target="_blank"&gt;Japanese&lt;/a&gt;). We want to thank all the volunteers for helping us make Picovico available to their native countries. We'll soon be extending our support to more countries. We'd love to discuss our existing translations or have suggestions on a &lt;a title="Volunteers needed for Picovico" href="http://www.picovico.com/volunteers" target="_blank"&gt;future translation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Along with this, we have recently crossed &lt;strong&gt;300,000 photos&lt;/strong&gt; uploads. We hope that you keep loving Picovico and we continue to touch the lives of people in the days to come :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are also coming up with some more awesome features. Will let ya all know soon when we are done with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Till then, Keep using Picovico and Happy Holidays!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="photos"></category><category term="Spanish"></category><category term="Japanese"></category><category term="Espanol"></category><category term="Videos"></category><category term="Startup Chile"></category><category term="Chile"></category><category term="Santiago"></category><category term="Photo-Video"></category><category term="Slideshow"></category></entry><entry><title>From Photo to Video Mode</title><link href="http://blog.picovico.com/from-photo-to-video-mode.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-09-27T07:54:58+05:45</updated><author><name>PICOVICO</name></author><id>tag:blog.picovico.com,2012-09-27:from-photo-to-video-mode.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="theme/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/logo.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-489" title="logo" src="theme/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/logo.jpg" alt="from photo to video" width="535" height="55" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recently we got covered in India’s leading national daily “The Hindu”.
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here is an excerpt: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;Most photo-sharing sites are about simple uploads of photos. But PicoVico (www.picovico.com) promises a difference. Here you can use your photos to create video slideshows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is created by young entrepreneurs Manish Modi and Suraj Sapkota.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Picovico.com came about when they realized that waiting for photos to load in conventional photo-sharing sites was boring and a waste of time. “We thought creating seamless videos from photos will help users convey the story behind the memories and save time as well,” says Modi. In &lt;a title="Picovico" href="http://www.picovico.com" target="_blank"&gt;Picovico&lt;/a&gt;, Pico stands for photos and Vico for videos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Modi and Sapkota did their computer engineering together and are programmers who love to code. Suraj is an avid photographer too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The site has four basic steps to create a video,” says Modi. “Users can select the style of presentation from the many templates we have, add photos and text, select music of their choice and then put in the titles and credits. Once these four steps are completed the video is created in a minute. You can export the video to Facebook or Youtube.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read the entire article here - &lt;a href="http://www.thehindu.com/sci-tech/technology/from-photo-to-video-mode/article3929666.ece" target="_blank"&gt;http://www.thehindu.com/sci-tech/technology/from-photo-to-video-mode/article3929666.ece&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="Photo-Video"></category><category term="Slideshow"></category><category term="Slideshow Maker"></category><category term="photography"></category><category term="Video Maker"></category></entry><entry><title>Picovico is now a part of "Start-Up Chile"</title><link href="http://blog.picovico.com/picovico-is-now-a-part-of-start-up-chile.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-09-01T10:48:06+05:45</updated><author><name>PICOVICO</name></author><id>tag:blog.picovico.com,2012-09-01:picovico-is-now-a-part-of-start-up-chile.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;We are so excited to share with you this good news - we are now a part of startup chile. Yea, &lt;a href="http://www.picovico.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Picovico&lt;/a&gt; has been selected for Start-Up Chile’s fifth generation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="theme/wp-content/uploads/2012/09/Start-Up-Chile-20121.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter  wp-image-166" title="Start-Up Chile 2012" src="theme/wp-content/uploads/2012/09/Start-Up-Chile-20121.jpg" alt="Picovico Journey to Chile" width="510" height="300" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://startupchile.org/" target="_blank"&gt;Start-up Chile&lt;/a&gt; is a program created by the Govt. of Chile that seeks to attract high-potential entrepreneurs to bootstrap their startups in Chile, using it as a platform to go global.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hailing from 37 nations,&lt;a href="http://startupchile.org/congrats-ya´ll/" target="_blank"&gt;101 teams&lt;/a&gt; were selected from a very competitive pool of 1509 applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last year, Picovico was selected by “&lt;a href="http://themorpheus.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Morpheus Venture Partners&lt;/a&gt;”, a startup accelerator based in india, which mentored Picovico team for development of the product. During the period, many new features and dynamics were added to the product. We thank Sameer and Nandini, Co-Founders/Mentors-duo from Morpheus, for being such an amazing mentors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This selection is cheered by the Picovico Team and we all are excited about it. The news has added excitement and zeal in the team to take it to greater heights. We expect to expand the team and get international exposure, and promise to build exciting features into the product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will be moving soon to Santiago for the program. We will keep you updated. Till then &lt;em&gt;hasta la vista. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="Start-Up Chile"></category><category term="Press"></category><category term="Santigo"></category><category term="Startup"></category></entry><entry><title>Have a Story? - Express</title><link href="http://blog.picovico.com/have-a-story-express.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-05-25T07:36:17+05:45</updated><author><name>PICOVICO</name></author><id>tag:blog.picovico.com,2012-05-25:have-a-story-express.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Expression is the soul &amp;amp; language of mankind and the essence of human heart. Life is devoid of charm, sweetness and that tenderness of love without expressing our feelings. And hence we, at Picovico, intend to make this world diabetic with the sweetness of expression spreading like an epidemic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.picovico.com/play/f2caae51fd954ab39ac7b39dc808b9ef?utm_source=picovicoblog&amp;amp;utm_medium=video&amp;amp;utm_content=post-134" target='_blank'&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-142" title="As you were always by my side" src="theme/wp-content/uploads/2012/05/as_you_were.png" alt="Video Thumbnail" width="640" height="360" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We vouch that there will be no lines of territories and region beholding it. YES, the world should fall in for Picovico and never feel goose bumps or trembling feet while expressing. Be it the gesture of care for your parents, those promises of togetherness for friends or the affection to your love, all lead to us. We believe that relations would become more bonded, because Picovico Team has that inherent passion to make it happen. Not very long from now, we aim to become synonymous to this word – ‘express’.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="video"></category><category term="Story"></category></entry><entry><title>A Gift for your Mom</title><link href="http://blog.picovico.com/a-gift-for-your-mom.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-05-10T12:12:10+05:45</updated><author><name>PICOVICO</name></author><id>tag:blog.picovico.com,2012-05-10:a-gift-for-your-mom.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p id="internal-source-marker_0.012883906498543762" dir="ltr"&gt;Every Child is special...but, ‘so is every mother’. Regardless of the amount of money you accumulate, the height of success you attain, or the fame that your name earns, you will always remain your mom’s child, and you will remain indebted to her for all the love she gave you, for all the blessings she showered upon you, for all the sacrifices she made for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="text-align: center;" dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;a href="http://bit.ly/pv-happy-mother-day" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-126" title="Mother's Day Image" src="theme/wp-content/uploads/2012/05/mothers_day.png" alt="Mother's Day Image" width="640" height="360" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;A mother plays myriad of roles in our lives, which can’t really be put down in a sheet of paper. She is a gentle touch, a soft lullaby, a pillar of strength, an epitome of love, a friend, a confidante, and everything beautiful that comes with life. It is rightly said, “God could not be everywhere, so he (it) created mothers.” How very true this is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;At some point of time in life, every child feels the need to thank his/her mother for everything she does. You probably recall all the blissful moments that you have shared with your mother, and you know deep down how grateful you are to her for being there for you, every day. But, it is very much likely that you have not been able to express those emotions, those feelings, those sentiments to your mother. This is very natural, but we are here to help you show your gratitude to your mother.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;This Mother’s Day, do something special for her, and let her know what she means to you. Thank her with a personalized video that she can treasure for life. Collect some pictures of you and her and that lovely childhood being bestowed with love from her, blend it with some lovely music and create a lifetime memory in the form of a video for the special woman in your life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;And this is not the end of it. We understand what mothers mean to all of us. So, to make the day even more special, we have a deal for you. Make the best possible video on the theme of motherhood, share it on our official &lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/picovico"&gt;facebook page&lt;/a&gt; and you can be the lucky one to win a free upgrade to the premium account in &lt;a href="http://www.picovico.com/"&gt;Picovico&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;And yes, do not forget to share your videos with us, we would love to see them :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;Happy Mother’s Day!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="mother's day"></category><category term="gift"></category><category term="memories"></category></entry><entry><title>10,000+ Photos Upload</title><link href="http://blog.picovico.com/10000-photos-upload.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-04-13T21:08:58+05:45</updated><author><name>PICOVICO</name></author><id>tag:blog.picovico.com,2012-04-13:10000-photos-upload.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update 05/01/2013: More than 300,000 photo uploads. :) :D &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Picovico reaches the milestone of 10k photos upload in just 2 weeks of &lt;a href="http://www.picovico.com/blog/picovico-public-beta-release.html" target="_blank"&gt;launching&lt;/a&gt;. We are really happy to see this tremendous response and can already sense the big wave of photos coming in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="theme/wp-content/uploads/2012/04/picovico_2.png"&gt;&lt;img class=" wp-image-96 alignleft" style="margin-bottom: 20px;" title="10,000 Photos Upload" src="theme/wp-content/uploads/2012/04/picovico_2.png" alt="" width="500" height="250" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;It has definitely added a new energy to Picovico and we are excited to bring in some cool features that would enhance your experience of video making.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are equally proud to inform you that Picovico has the fastest video creation platform, which comes from the sophisticated GPU engine for video processing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are committed towards bringing more innovation and making your video creation and sharing, a seamless experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Its the coolest way to give life to your photos. Give Picovico a try.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="photos"></category><category term="upload"></category><category term="GPU"></category></entry><entry><title>Let your video go social!</title><link href="http://blog.picovico.com/let-your-video-go-social.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-04-10T18:54:40+05:45</updated><author><name>PICOVICO</name></author><id>tag:blog.picovico.com,2012-04-10:let-your-video-go-social.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;Since the release of Picovico two weeks back, we have seen tremendous response from users. We have seen a lot of interest, received a lot of queries, and a lot of encouragement. Innovation is a process. Million thanks to all our users who are constantly helping us upgrade our product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;a href="theme/wp-content/uploads/2012/04/picovico-export-yoututbe-facebook.png"&gt;&lt;img class="alignleft" title="Export to Youtube/Facebook" src="theme/wp-content/uploads/2012/04/picovico-export-yoututbe-facebook.png" alt="Export to Youtube/Facebook" width="158" height="465" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;Over the past two weeks, we received a lot of e-mails asking us if the Picovico videos could be exported to Youtube and Facebook. In order to make the Picovico experience a lot more fun, we have added this new feature — Picovico now allows you to export your videos directly to Facebook and Youtube! \m/&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;This can be done by following few simple steps. On the video page, &lt;span style="text-decoration: underline;"&gt;click on &lt;em&gt;‘Video Settings’&lt;/em&gt; &amp;gt; &lt;em&gt;‘Export to Youtube’&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;‘Export to Facebook’&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt; to release your video to youtube and facebook respectively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;This new feature will allow you to share your beautiful memories with your family members, friends, and people in your network. Did someone not say, ‘Happiness multiplies when shared.’ So, be ready to share your joy with others!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;If you are not very enthusiastic about exporting your video to Facebook/Youtube, it is perfectly alright. You can still share the direct video link with your loved ones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;And yes, you can expect a lot more features from Picovico lab. Our team is working hard to give that perfect tool to you!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="facebook"></category><category term="youtube"></category><category term="social-video"></category><category term="export"></category></entry><entry><title>Picovico gets featured on Yourstory.in</title><link href="http://blog.picovico.com/picovico-gets-featured-on-yourstory-in.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-04-04T10:00:08+05:45</updated><author><name>PICOVICO</name></author><id>tag:blog.picovico.com,2012-04-04:picovico-gets-featured-on-yourstory-in.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong id="internal-source-marker_0.8616769430227578"&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="theme/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/yslogo-black.png"&gt;&lt;img class=" wp-image-417 alignleft" title="yourstory logo" src="theme/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/yslogo-black-300x84.png" alt="picovico" width="192" height="54" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span&gt; feels great when one gets recognized for the effort and hard work one puts in his/her work. We felt the same when &lt;/span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a title="Slideshow Maker" href="www.picovico.com" target="_blank"&gt;Picovico&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span&gt; was featured in India’s leading online platform for entrepreneurs - &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="http://yourstory.in/" target="_blank"&gt;Yourstory.in&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The article mainly speaks about how Picovico was created and got selected for &lt;a href="http://themorpheus.com/" target="_blank"&gt;The Morpheus Ventures&lt;/a&gt;. The article also talks about the trends in photo sharing on Social Media and how Picovico is putting a tremendous effort in changing the perception of sharing photos the traditional way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read the full article here: &lt;a href="http://yourstory.in/2012/04/picovico-com-a-morpheus-gang-company-lets-you-collate-photos-make-memorable-videos-easily/" target="_blank"&gt;http://yourstory.in/2012/04/picovico-com-a-morpheus-gang-company-lets-you-collate-photos-make-memorable-videos-easily/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="picovico"></category><category term="Startup"></category><category term="Slideshow Maker"></category><category term="feature"></category><category term="photo-sharing"></category><category term="trends"></category><category term="entrepreneurs"></category><category term="business"></category></entry><entry><title>Public Beta Release</title><link href="http://blog.picovico.com/picovico-public-beta-release.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-03-25T04:46:36+05:45</updated><author><name>PICOVICO</name></author><id>tag:blog.picovico.com,2012-03-25:picovico-public-beta-release.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;div style="text-align: justify;"&gt;"If a picture is worth a thousand words, then a video must be worth millions of words". This has been our motto at Picovico ever since it was conceived. Finally after almost a year of restless development we are pleased to announce the public beta release of &lt;a href="http://www.picovico.com/" target="_blank"&gt;www.picovico.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div style="text-align: justify;"&gt;Picovico is a cloud based video creation platform. It takes a set of images, blends it with the music and produces a beautiful video plotted alongside your story. The core intelligent system has formed the brain of Picovico and thus keeps you away from the hectic task of defining the effects and animations.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;Video making with Picovico is easy and seamless:
- Upload your images or import from facebook/flickr
- Optionally, add captions to your images
- Select music from our library or upload your own
- And rest back, while we do the rest for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;Once the video is ready, you can share it with your friends or even export it to other online-video-sharing-&lt;wbr&gt;platforms.&lt;/wbr&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;Videos created with Picovico are more than just videos, they are memories. Give it a spin!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;Register Now: &lt;a title="http://www.picovico.com/" href="http://www.picovico.com"&gt;www.picovico.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;View Sample videos at: &lt;a href="http://www.picovico.com/sample-videos"&gt;http://www.picovico.com/sample-videos&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;</summary><category term="Release"></category><category term="Beta"></category></entry><entry><title>Introducing Picovico</title><link href="http://blog.picovico.com/introducing-picovico.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-04-27T21:53:05+05:45</updated><author><name>PICOVICO</name></author><id>tag:blog.picovico.com,2011-04-27:introducing-picovico.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;There is nothing like joy of sharing photographs online. Last night’s dinner, cousins birthday bash, parents dance-in together, or the band’s concert- don’t we share everything. And why not? One can tag  friends and the moments, get comments from everywhere, envy few friends and make statement on the web-social world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;We intend to take this marvel experience to next level by introducing our latest &lt;strong&gt;Facebook Application&lt;/strong&gt; called &lt;strong&gt;PicoVico&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;strong&gt;PicoVico&lt;/strong&gt; will help you convert your online photo albums into cool video with the music and effect of your choice. Your college farewell party or your office pizza break: they all can become your own video &lt;em&gt;(How about that?)&lt;/em&gt; You can tag friends, choose the sound tracks, visual effects among others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;So, log into Facebook, and share your experience with Pico Vico touch. Not only it will help you to enhance your creativity in your own photographs but also help you make compilation of favorite movies, sports stars, cars or clubs.(H&lt;em&gt;ow about your own photo shoot video.&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;“They say a picture is worth thousand words. We assure you that your video would be worth million words ”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;[&lt;em&gt; Introducing the new kid in the town of facebook. The kid is looking for friends!! The friends who have picture!! The pictures which means them a lot!! A lot, yes lot so that they can make video from  them! The video in your facebook!! just few clicks away!! Away: Not exactly]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;Please leave your comments&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="facebook"></category><category term="facebook app"></category><category term="photos"></category><category term="video"></category><category term="image"></category><category term="share"></category><category term="youtube"></category></entry></feed>